Leifur Castle - Front End Engineer

(208) 310-2163 · leifurcastle@gmail.com · Ferndale, Wa · https://github.com/LeifCastle

Front end engineering graduate from General Assembly with expertise in Javascript and Python, and experience creating applications with frameworks such as Next, React, and Django. Strong problem-solving skills coupled with a background in customer service and team leadership enhances ability to deliver outstanding results.

Skills

Languages - Javascript, Python, HTML5, CSS, SQL

Libraries and Frameworks - React, Next, Django, Node, Express.js, Tailwind CSS

Database/Other - MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Selenium, Git, Github, Postman, Microsoft Excel

Software Development Projects

BirthdayBuzz (In Progress) - www.birthdaybuz.net Automated birthday email reminder tool August 2023 - Present

- Frontend built with Next and Javascript, user accounts require email verification implemented with Twilio's API
- Back-end RESTful API server built with Node, Express.js, and MongoDB Atlas cloud database
- Utilized MongoDB & Mongoose to allow users to save friends and family to their "Buzz List"
- Integrated Heroku Scheduler to run daily scripts fulfilling each users' Buzz List reminder requests
- Automatic emailing implemented with SendGrid's service API
- Frontend to backend seamless communication achieved with Axios HTTP requests, often sent with accompanying data in JSON format, and user authentication implemented with passport.js
- Collaborated with the team as a Git Master using Git forking workflow procedures and frequent commits
- Successfully deployed backend and frontend to Heroku with a custom domain (www.birthdaybuz.net)

Colorz - www.colorznow.com Layout based theme creation tool

July 2023 - August 2023

- Utilized Next and Javascript to create a dynamic front-end application boasting user accounts, wireframing tools, color and styling options, and user theme to CSS color pallet exportation
- Employed React hooks to create drag & drop resizable widgets capable of quickly wireframing an existing or new website's basic layout and text
- Full background, text, and font customization enables users to immediately visualize how color choices would look on their website through the wireframe's representation.
- Implemented a back-end RESTful API server using Node and Express.is and an integrated MongoDB database
- Enabled users to save themes to a User model of multi-level embedded documents with MongoDB & Mongoose
- Achieved seamless front to backend communication with Axios and user authentication with passport.js
- Collaborated with the team as a Git Master using Git forking workflow procedures and frequent commits
- Successfully deployed backend and frontend to Heroku with a custom domain (www.colorznow.com)

Professional Experience

The Home Depot - Retail Cashier/Service Desk/Pro | Bellingham, Wa

May 2023 - Present

- Attained mastery in operating Home Depot's software systems as a cashier, service desk representative, pro
 associate, and paint associate, resulting in efficient and accurate customer transactions.
- Demonstrated exceptional problem-solving abilities by resolving customer issues in a friendly and effective manner, fostering positive customer experiences and driving customer satisfaction.

JDP Renovations - Lead Laborer | Moscow, Id

Oct 2020 - June 2022

• Led a small team of two in renovations/additions for three houses, teaching both coworkers rudimentary carpentry, trim, plumbing, electrical, and tool skills along the way

Education

General Assembly | Remote Software Engineering Immersive

Feb 2023 - August 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.